<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yicong Zheng</title>
    <link>https://zycyc.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yicong Zheng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 10:41:17 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zycyc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography</title>
      <link>https://zycyc.github.io/projects/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zycyc.github.io/projects/photography/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy taking photos everywhere I go.
They form the trace of my life and more importantly, my personal visual diary.
My cameras include Nikon D5200, iPhone 7, iPhone SE (emeritus) and Mi 4 (emeritus).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Memory</title>
      <link>https://zycyc.github.io/projects/mm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zycyc.github.io/projects/mm/</guid>
      <description>How does human learn music? The one simple answer will be repeatedly listening, but what&amp;rsquo;s the underlying neural mechanism that supports this learning process? Better memory performance is predicted by higher representational similarity between encoding and retrieval (Xue, 2010), is memory of music the same? Beyond this question, I also want to find out how cortex and hippocampus represent musical features like tempo, pitch, rhythm, and how these two representations interact to depict music learning curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serial Dependence</title>
      <link>https://zycyc.github.io/projects/sd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zycyc.github.io/projects/sd/</guid>
      <description>We tend to perceive the world around us as stable in space and time, a study by Fischer and Whitney (2014) suggests that human visual perception is serially dependent, using both prior and present input to inform perception at the present moment. Specifically, perceived orientation in an orientation judgment task is likely biased towards previously seen stimuli.
While I was an exchange student in UC Berkeley during Spring 2019 semester, I did replication and relevant experiments both on-line and off-line with Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Sequence</title>
      <link>https://zycyc.github.io/projects/ts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zycyc.github.io/projects/ts/</guid>
      <description>Using similar paradigm with this paper (Crivelli-Decker, Hsieh, Clarke &amp;amp; Ranganath, 2018), we are trying to use EEG to unravel the role of the mysterious theta/alpha oscillations in temporal sequence learning, and the difference between healthy people and schizophrenia patients.
Previous studies have found decreased oscillatory power in the theta (4-7Hz) band at frontal sites following decisions about objects in &amp;ldquo;consistent sequences&amp;rdquo;, compared to &amp;ldquo;random&amp;rdquo; sequences; and also increased parieto-occipital alpha (10-13Hz) power before decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Ideas</title>
      <link>https://zycyc.github.io/blog/research_ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 10:41:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zycyc.github.io/blog/research_ideas/</guid>
      <description>Since being in (Charan&amp;rsquo;s lab)[http://dml.ucdavis.edu] in Davis, I started to get the true feeling of research. It is not about pure passion in &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m doing something special&amp;rdquo;, but more like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m doing what attracts me&amp;rdquo;. To be honest, research could be hard and demanding, which probably means occupying tons of your time being stupid; nevertheless, I am still here and being satisfied. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any chance to publish anything, but it has already hypnotized me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is love?</title>
      <link>https://zycyc.github.io/blog/what_is_love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 23:54:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zycyc.github.io/blog/what_is_love/</guid>
      <description> It is simply another type of serial dependence (Manassi, 2019).
 It is when I stare at you and you stare at your stuffs.
 It is when I listen to my favorite song and look at your smile.
 It is when we finish our daily ritual and haste to hang up.
 It is reciprocal support and understanding.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Learning</title>
      <link>https://zycyc.github.io/blog/statistical_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 23:45:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zycyc.github.io/blog/statistical_learning/</guid>
      <description>Statistical Learning Recently is obsess with statistical learning (SL), and think that SL is literally applicable in everyday life event. Since I just think of some for now (most of them just skipped my head and it&amp;rsquo;s truly amazing feeling!), I will list them here.
 Perfect pitch practice in infants Non-native speaker learning English (or any other foreign language) by representation instead of translational understanding Everything related to pattern separation &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;  This is an immature thought, but SL could be an essential key to solve many specific cognition problems in the way of learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some simple thoughts for myself</title>
      <link>https://zycyc.github.io/blog/some_simple_thoughts_for_myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 20:25:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zycyc.github.io/blog/some_simple_thoughts_for_myself/</guid>
      <description>Since being here in Berkely, life has become busy and full. I can imagine after a day of classes and RA works, I&amp;rsquo;ll just have no time and energy left for my private business, and that&amp;rsquo;s definitely not &amp;ldquo;cool&amp;rdquo;. Being a potential researcher in cognitive science is hard but full of surprises and the kind of feeling that I want. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it is general, but everytime I got that feeling, I would be just like &amp;ldquo;fast recharged&amp;rdquo; and happy to accept everything imperfect in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>